Pray, God dammit.
-You want your mama to die? -No, sir.
Then pray!
Lord, please save my mama!
-Clean the cancer inside of her! -We need your help!
Now you pray, now! You hear me?
Yes, Lord!
Save my mama, Lord!
Please clean the cancer inside of her!
And don't be crying, you hear? Don't be crying!
-Pray like you mean it! Lord!
Spare my wife!
Don't take her from me.
Fuck.
-Fuck!
We gotta do something. The Japs just left him up there.
Next stop, Meade, Ohio.
Next time, the cops will drag you out.
-Excuse me. -Get out!
I'm just gonna take my break outside.
All right.
-All right!
-Welcome. - Willard.
Willard, I've asked Helen to sit with us. Go on, Helen.
-Nice to meet you. -Hi, how are you?
Willard just got back, Helen.
-You-- -Welcome home.
It's been four days.
Willard didn't know that Emma had promised God
that in exchange for bringing him home safe,
she'd make sure he married Helen Hatton.
The girl's family burned up in a house fire
It's hot, ain't it?
-Amen. -It's bound to get hotter.
Right now, we got two boys from over in Topperville
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Now, you pray on what happened today.
-God!
-Stubbs! -Stubbs, get out here, man!
-Get out of here! -Come on, give me a hand.
Get the fuck out of here!
Now you remember what I told you?
That's what I meant.
Just gotta pick the right time.
Yes, sir.
There's a lot of no good sons of bitches out there.
-More than a hundred?
Yeah, at least that many.
How about I buy you a candy bar, huh?
We gotta get some sugar for Mama too.
Mama?
-Mama?
Dad!
-Mama!
No! Charlotte!
Listen to me. Charlotte!
-What are you saying? -The test results aren't good.
The morphine will continue to dampen the pain but...
there's no way we can destroy that cancer.
Let's talk downstairs.
Now... them doctors can't do your mom any good.
Dad, no!
Dad!
Lord, this here is my boy's dog.
Now you take him!
Bring him back!
You save Charlotte!
Before I found the Holy Ghost...
I was scared plumb to death of spiders.
-Ain't that right, Theodore? -Mm-hmm.
-Mm? -Hmm.
Helen did, in fact, meet the man she would marry that afternoon.
Bless me, Reverend.
Bless me.
And Willard's mind was already hundreds of miles away.
Lenora...
Roy?
Where about?
C-Coal Creek, West Virginia.
We'll get you close enough, son.
I'm Carl, by the way, this here's Sandy.
-Sister fucker. -He would do anything to protect her.
No matter what the weather was,
Lenora would visit her mother's grave after school.
Some days she'd even read the Bible out loud,
and imagine her mother was listening.
Though he wasn't one for praying
Arvin would often drive her and keep her company.
Happy birthday.
All right.
Make a wish before that candle burns out.
Hello there.
Pleased to meet you, Reverend.
Emma Russell.
Nice to meet you too. What you got there?
there's no doubt...
we're all humble people gathered here.
-Amen. -Amen.
Y'all have been awful nice to me
and I thank you from the bottom of my heart for the welcome.
-Yes.
But friends...
the poor soul...
Lenora...
have you truly opened yourself to the Lord with...
Preacher Sykes or...
any other preacher?
Come on, she likes lanky old studs like yourself. Come on.
What's going on here, mister?
Oh, come on, Jesus Christ, huh?
Pay attention. It's like I said, you're gonna fuck my wife
and I'm gonna take some pictures, that's all.
I got another election coming up, Sandy.
Ol' Matthew's out there doing anything he can to try to make me look bad.
Is Carl the one pimping you? That fat son of a bitch?
No, he's working, making deliveries.
for some wrong done to you by another person.
That's true.
remember all the things we did in your car?
I'm saying you must be crazy.
Coming in the Lord's house and talking all this trash.
Look, my advice to you, girl...
Grandma!
No, no, no!
No one would know she wasn't a suicide
and that in the end, she was all right with her maker.
Oh, Lord.
But you take her into your arms.
Uh, ain't somebody...
saying prayers or...
Excuse me.
So...
Mrs. Russell's boy?
All right.
Don't do anything you'll regret, son.
Why don't you put the gun down and...
we can talk all about it.
It wasn't my fault.
And Lenora...
was just like this...
this Reaster girl.
She wouldn't let me be.
But I want you to know that I--
I pray for that girl's soul
every night.
Carl?
I see him.
-We don't even know where he's going. -Carl?
-Just-- -God dammit, Carl.
He's going to Ohio.
No one from home. That's your rule.
Morning.
Where you headed?
Meade, Ohio. You heard of it?
The paper-mill town, right?
Yeah, that's right.
We're passing right through it.
What you going to Meade for?
-Just visiting. -Got family there?
No, I used to live there a long time ago.
Damn. That's gonna be one fine sunset.
You have to be patient with me while I get a few shots off.
Hon, give me the key.
Don't you worry none. We've got some hooch in the back and...
Well, Sandy's good company.
I'm sorry, Lee. This is fucked up.
What do you mean?
It's your sister and her husband.
Carl was shot twice.
Sandy once.
It looks like it was a nine millimeter.
Sandy got one shot off but...
her gun was loaded with blanks.
-Jesus Christ. -Lee?
Give me a couple minutes here alone with her.
Still there?
Well, I'll be damned.
You're that Russell boy, ain't you?
I just thought, seeing as I was this way, I'd stop by and see the old place again.
Son, I hate to tell you this, but that place burned some years ago.
They think some kids did it.
Wasn't nobody ever living there since you and your folks.
Well, heck, I come all this way, I may as well walk up there anyways.
Sure, just cut across Clarence's pasture.
He won't say nothing.
I never did thank you for the night my dad died.
You were awful kind of me,
and I just want you to know that I ain't never forgot it.
Arvin thought about the days leading up to his mother's death,
how Willard wanted so much for her to live.
Fuck the blood and stink, the heat and the insects.
Anything.
Arvin said to himself.
And suddenly he realized, standing in his father's church,
that he'd had no other choice,
that Willard had needed to go wherever Charlotte went.
Arvin Russell!
I know you're down there somewhere!
It's Sheriff Bodecker, son!
Got some questions to ask you!
Sorry about that!
Goddamn bird scared me.
I ain't here to hurt you!
And I know that you don't wanna hurt me!
Come on out so we can have us a talk!
I had no choice!
I hate to be the one to tell you this, Sheriff, but your sister...
and her husband, they weren't no good neither!
I got a snapshot in my pocket here of her hugging on some dead guy.
You let loose that gun and I'll show it to you!
And that girl that's living with them...
She's just a little younger than you.
Maybe we'll stay for a while.
Arvin.
When Dad goes to sleep...
I'm going to bring you down and give you a proper burial.
Durham, North Carolina.
Though the poor fucker had been completely worthless as a model,
Carl was insistent on keeping a record
of both his successes and his failures.